{
    "question": "Buatlah kalimat berikut present perfect tensse 2. He (study) English for 3 years.    3.1 (live) in Kebumen for 15 years.\r\n\r\n4.1 (smoke) since I was a child. 5. They (eat) it all.\r\n\r\n6. We (work) for 5 hours.\r\n\r\n8. We (submit) the assignment on time 9. He (do) it perfectly\u200b",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>2. He has studied English for 3 years.</p><p>3. I have lived in Kebumen for 15 years.</p><p>4. I have smoked since I was a child.</p><p>5. They have eaten it all.</p><p>6. We have worked for 5 hours.</p><p>8. We have submitted the assignment on time.</p><p>9. He has done it perfectly.</p><p></p><p>Formula: </p><p>S + have or has + past participle.</p><p>S + have not (haven&#039;t) or has not (hasn&#039;t) + past participle</p>",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "kamu-sudah-makan-bahasa-inggrisnya-865",
            "question": "Kamu sudah makan bahasa Inggrisnya \r\n\r\n\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>kamu sudah makan bahasa inggris nya adalah <strong>Have </strong><strong>you </strong><strong>eaten</strong></p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p><em>semoga </em><em>bermanfaat</em></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>Have you eaten??</p><p>semoga membantu yaa:v</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "1-write-a-procedure-text-how-to-make-a-label-553",
            "question": "1. write a procedure text : how to make a label\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p><strong> ini terjemahan nya yaa</strong></p><p><strong><u>1. tulis teks prosedur : cara membuat label</u></strong> </p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Ketik nama </p><p>buat daftar </p><p>buat alamat </p><p>dan setelah itu pengiriman </p><p></p><p></p><p><strong>kala</strong><strong>u</strong><strong> </strong><strong>mau</strong><strong> </strong><strong>mengir</strong><strong>im</strong><strong> </strong><strong>:</strong><strong>)</strong><strong> </strong></p><p></p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "19-the-opposite-of-poor-is-rich-o-o-o-o-lazy-o-handsome-o-914",
            "question": "19. The opposite of poor is ...\r\n*\r\nrich\r\nO O O\r\nO lazy\r\nO handsome\r\nO\r\nO\r\nsmart\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>rich </p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Kebalikan dari miskin adalah kaya, dalam bahasa Inggris \"rich\"</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "18-wulan-what-is-your-plan-tonight-arbi-i-will-watch-a-movi-553",
            "question": "18. Wulan     : What is your plan tonight?\r\nArbi\r\n: I will watch a movie at home\r\nWulan : What movie are you going to watch?\r\nArbi : I don't know yet. Perhaps I will watch drama movie.\r\nWulan : You should watch education movie. It's good to add our knowledge.\r\nArbi : It sounds good to me.\r\nThe underline sentence in the dialogue above shows the expression of....\r\na. asking for plan\r\nd. giving advice\r\nb. asking for help\r\ne. giving information\r\nC. asking for advice\r\n\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><h2>a. Asking for plan.</h2><p></p><h3>Penjelasan:</h3><p>Ini jawabannnya ya. </p><p>Terima Kasih.</p><h3>klo salah maap ya :)</h3>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "2-clair-dad-can-i-borrow-your-car-i-need-to-go-to-alans-hous-617",
            "question": "2. CLAIR: Dad, can I borrow your car? i need to go to Alan's house to do our homework together    FATHER Please make sure that you get home before 8 pm\r\nCLAIR Thanks. Dad\r\nI'm afraid you can't\r\nC. Yes, you can\r\nI'm sorry, I need the car\r\nD. No, thanks\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>2. CLAIR: Dad, can I borrow your car? i need to go to Alan&#039;s house to do our homework together\n</p><p>FATHER Please make sure that you get home before 8 pm\n</p><p>CLAIR Thanks. Dad\n</p><p>I&#039;m afraid you can&#039;t\n</p><p><strong>C. Yes, you can</strong>\n</p><p>I&#039;m sorry, I need the car\n</p><p>D. No, thanks\u200b</p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Jawaban dicetak tebal dan ditentukan dari reaksi Clair yang berterima kasih pada ayahnya, maka jawabannya adalah poin C. Yes, you can. Pilihan lain semuanya salah.</p><p>Semoga membantu ya.</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-bantu-yang-bisa-bahasa-inggris-mau-dikumpulin-jangan-ngasa-199",
            "question": "Tolong bantu yang bisa bahasa inggris mau dikumpulin jangan ngasal ya\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>gimna mau ngebantu soalnya aj g ada</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-soal-pilihan-ganda-neither-nor-457",
            "question": "Contoh soal pilihan ganda neither nor",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>contoh soal pilihan ganda neither nor</p><p>1. Neither Budi .......... Badu came to the party last night.</p><p>a. or</p><p>b. nor</p><p>c. and</p><p>d. but</p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Kalimat di atas merupakan contoh soal pilihan ganda dari neither nor yang jawabannya adalah poin b. nor.</p><p>Semoga membantu ya.</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "a-fish-live-on-the-tolong-bantu-jawab-358",
            "question": "A fish live on the....\r\nTolong bantu jawab\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>water</p><p>sea</p><p>ocean</p><p>dead sea</p><p>lakes</p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>intinya ikan hidup di dalam air brother</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "a fish lives on the\u2026<br>artinya: \u201cikan hidup di\u2026\u201d<br><br>ikan hidup dimana? laut/danau/sungai/delta/kolam/muara<br><br>karena banyak banget kita pilih yang paling umum aja ya, laut <br><br>laut bahasa inggrisnya sea<br><br>jadi jawabanya\u2026 <br><br>\u201ca fish lives on the sea\u201d",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "6-would-you-mind-not-closing-the-window-the-sentence-has-the-615",
            "question": "6. \"Would you mind not closing the window?\"    The sentence has the same meaning with :\r\nA. Do not close the window, please.\r\nB. Close the window, please,\r\nC. The window must be closed\r\nD. Don't open the window, please.\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>A. Do not close the window, please.</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "c-e-a-a-f-o-v-l-the-correct-word-is-382",
            "question": "C\u2013E\u2013A\u2013A\u2013F\u2013O\u2013V\u2013L\r\nthe correct word is... \u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>ga ada</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}